<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[emersonacademy]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[emersonacademy]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/emersonacademy/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 09:07:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/emersonacademy/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The SAT & Other Test Scores]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The SAT & Other Test Scores</h1><p>Classical education produces students who reason effectively, think deeply, speak persuasively, and write rhetorically. However, the benefits of classical education are evident in real numbers. Latin students score the highest out of all foreign language learners on the SAT Reading and Writing (college entrance exam), the highest out of all 270 majors on the GRE (graduate school entrance exam), and the highest out of all takers of the MCAT (medical school entrance exam) in Verbal Reasoning, excelling the Chemistry major in Biological Sciences and the Biology major in both Biological Sciences and in Physical Sciences, according to the National Test Scores of Classics Students.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/emersonacademy/the-sat-and-other-test-scores/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">38138681-eb54-4d42-9a46-477d5933ddb2</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 09:07:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Is Liberal Education?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>What Is Liberal Education?</h1><p>The Association of American Colleges and Universities describes liberal education as “a philosophy of education that empowers individuals with broad knowledge and transferable skills, and a stronger sense of values, ethics, and civic engagement…characterized by challenging encounters with important issues.” In the early years of the 21st century, many universities and liberal arts colleges throughout the United States reviewed their curricula to include a liberal education or to promote broader undergraduate education infused with its spirit.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/emersonacademy/what-is-liberal-education/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">dfe30934-8463-4427-8dd2-9114a84033c5</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 09:03:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Is Classical Education?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>What Is Classical Education?</h1><p> With its beginning in ancient Greece and Rome, classical education flourished during the Middle Ages and the Renaissance, becoming the primary rite of passage for the intellectual elite throughout all the other great historical epochs of western civilization until the advent of modern progressive education in the 20th century. Classical education teaches the student to think clearly and to love beauty and the past. It trains the mind to analyze and draw conclusions. The student learns how to spot patterns and principles, how to solve problems and tie in new ideas. It demands self-discipline and perseverance. Classical education is language-intensive, with reading, writing, grammar, logic, and rhetoric at the center of the curriculum. It is history-intensive, providing the student with a holistic view of human endeavors through the great classics from the beginning until now.Classical education is systematic. Every element of the curriculum is fully integrated, building upon one another. The curriculum is tightly structured, starting at the Logic Stage (5th-8th grades), during which the student perfects the skill of abstracting from particulars, to the Rhetoric Stage (9th-12th grades), during which the student uses his argumentative skills developed at the Logic Stage for self-expression in speech and writing. Classical education is rigorous. Emerson’s language curriculum in classical grammar, classical logic, and classical rhetoric is vastly different in scope and content from what is currently taught in schools today. Our materials have been time-honored: We do not use modern American textbooks with their fragmented incoherency and skittish content but the original works of only the great authors that have withstood the test of time. </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/emersonacademy/what-is-classical-education/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">19e352f9-93bd-4cf5-b2cb-4b70997d4454</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 08:51:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>